Hadi Lashkari Ghouchani

Software Engineer

@ hi@hadilq.com

hadilg.com

O Toronto, Canada

github.com/hadilq

@hadilq@androiddev.social

in linkedin.com/in/hadilq

Summary

A humble and curious developer with over 19 years of experience in software development, where 9 years of his experience covers professional Android development, over 2 years covers teaching algorithms and programming in universities, and over 8 years covers academic and self-employed experiences while he was a student.

An Introvert person who has profound contributing skills. A creative, value-driven developer who enjoys doing math, solving problems and creating scalable, maintainable, testable and efficient apps to make the world a better place to live. Advocate of bayesian mindsets. As a software architect, he pursue reproducible, frictionless, consistent, and scalable structures.

A person whose goal is to surround himself with creative, clever, motivative and happy engineers. He's especially good at understanding, designing, and applying software architectures, all kinds of automations, including CI/CD. Additionally, he's a big fan of SSOT, principle of ownership, isolation principle, pure functions, SOLID principles especially DIP.

He believes an open source resume would contribute to his credibility, even though, because of that the bullet points in this resume are degrading super fast in the market, therefore, just reach out. Maybe we'll be good

Experience

Productivity Engineer

at MobileLIVE

Aug, 2022 - Present

Toronto, Canada

Promoted to "Productivity Engineer" of Mobility team in Bell Canada to make tools and automate processes of the development life cycle to improve productivity.

- Investigated problems related to proxy and self-signed certificates in VPN networks, where by implementing a script, and by using a Jetpack Compose Desktop app to install them automatically increased the build count in GE dashboard by 164%.
- Raised and implemented the need for Gradle Conventional Plugins to reduce duplication and errors. This also applied SSOT on versions of external libraries, which reduced the runtime crashes due to version
- Raised the idea and created a workflow POC in Gitlab to showcase how to achieve code quality by using Merge Trains and Merge request pipelines.
- Decreased the time of running tests by 18%
- The single point of training and supporting for the build and its related issues in the team of 50+ Android developers

Additional Technologies

Gradle Enterprise, Gradle Conventional Plugin, Jetpack Compose Desktop.

Software Engineer

at MobileLIVE

m Apr. 2021 - Aug. 2022

O Toronto, Canada

MobileLIVE is a Canadian tech-service provider unifying people, technology, and business to accelerate digital transformation. Over this time, he worked in Bell Canada as a full-time contractor. Bell Canada is subsidiary Bell Aliant provides services in the Atlantic provinces. It provides mobile service through its Bell Mobility (including Virgin Mobile Canada) subsidiary, and television through its Bell Satellite TV and Bell Fibe TV subsidiaries.

Mission:

- Introduced RFCs to make technical decisions and steps to applying on any new idea.
- · Added value by teaching and discussing SOLID principles, and best practices of modularization, feature
- Raised and implemented the idea of automatically cloning and building all the source code in the multirepo setup to reduce version conflicts, and improve code visibility for debugging purposes.

Technologies:

- Kotlin Coroutines / Mockk, Mockito, jUnit, etc.
 - Agile, Sprint, Lane based branching strategy, CI/CD
 - Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Gitlab, Jenkins, Slack, Branch.io, inVision, Dynatrace, etc.

Staff Android Developer

at iFood

m Oct. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Barcelona, Spain

iFood was an ambitious project to build an entire food delivery ecosystem for all around the world. Currently, it was the biggest food delivery in Brazil, Colombia and Mexico, with 50+ million apps installed on Android devices alone. The Android project was highly modularized to make it possible for 50+ developers working on it frictionlessly.

- Proposed and implemented composite build to handle dependency management in Gradle. It decreased the incremental build time while updating a library from more than 13 min to less than a minute.
- Implemented Android side of metadata project. Its purpose was gathering all information of the highly modularized Android/iOS projects in a dashboard along backend information.
- Proposed and applied a concept to move out the legacy code from the root module. It decreased the incremental build time by 55%.
- Detected many ANRs and resolved them by applying architectural principles. • Wrapped up external libraries to better handling panic situations

Technologies

- Dagger 2, Room, Kotlin Coroutines, Moshi, WorkManager / Mockk, Robolectric, jUnit, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD, Gradle Enterprise
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Databricks, Firebase, Bugsnag, Logzio, etc.

Senior Android Developer

at Letgo

m Oct. 2019 - Mar. 2021

Parcelona, Spain

15+ million apps installed on Android devices alone. TL;DR Mission: Improved the performance of loading feeds by at least a minute.

Lead Android Developer

at Sheypoor

Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor was one of two leading classified marketplaces in Iran with 1.5+ million users per day, 13+ million overall users and 344+ million sessions. TL;DR Mission: Increased the number of users per day from 0.5+million to 1.5+ million in a year.

Senior Android Developer

at Myket

Tehran, Iran

Myket was one of two leading app stores in Iran with over 8+ million users. TL;DR Mission: Implemented features in the Myket app store, started TDD, installed Jenking's pipeline to handle CI/CD.

Java and C# developer

at Soha System

mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

O Tehran, Iran

SOHA was formed to focus on solutions based on smart cards. TL;DR Mission: Implementted Android and

Article / Repository

- 2024 Sample Rust App: A sample app to crawl an API and put the data in a database.
 2024 Nix Effect pod: Modularize effects of all kinds, and stay in-control, with NixOS and podman.
- 🥱 2023 Sample App: Refactored a Mastodon client app to a modularized Jetpack Compose-driven architecture,
- LTA, which is designed by himself.

 M 2023 Post: Dependency Inversion Principle
- 2023 Contributing to nixpkgs/androidenv: Nix is a language that is designed to have reproducibile output.
- 1 2022 Post: Logic Tree in Android 2022 Sample App: Molecule sample app to solve some scoping problems in Android development.
- ✓ 2022 Sample App: Molecule sample app to solve some scoping problems in Android development.
 ✓ 2022 Post: Reproducibility
 ✓ 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Are feature flags, build variants, and sample apps related concepts?
 ✓ 2021 FroAndroidDev post: Modularization tip: optimize the Root Module.
 ✓ 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Happy Railway. An improvement for Railway Oriented Programming in Kotlin.
- 7 2021 Library: Happy is a library to auto-generate Kotlin code to make calling APIs more concise 2020 POC: Rust Flutter Reactive is an idea to use Flutter as UI and Rust for the main project. 2020 Make Log4k Multiplatform: Simple logging library for Android, iOS, Mac, etc.
- M 2020 ProAndroidDev post: A/B Testing Myths
 ☐ 2020 Sample App: Provide a full implementation for a No-Framework Dependency Injection in Kotlin
- \bigcirc 2020 Contributing on Λ rrow Library: Λ rrow is a library for Typed Functional Programming in Kotlin
- ↑ 2020 Library: A Kotlin compiler plugin that generates trackable method
 ↑ 2020 Medium post: Save State By Using RxJava or Kotlin Flow
 ↑ 2020 Medium post: RxJava instead of LiveData in MVVM
- 7 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and upstreams in RxJava 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and Kotlin Coroutines
- 2020 Library: Simplifier for unnecessary complex lifecycles 🔾 2019 Sample App: Functional Programming + Clean Architecture
- 2019 Sample App: Movie Challenge 🔾 2019 Math Library: Modularized, mathematical and multiplatform Kotlin library
- M 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Logging in Kotlin
- 2018 Log4k Library: Easy logging library, but unfortunately it's in Sheypoor repository

Education

Sharif University Of Technology

Payame Noor University

M.Sc

in Physics

in Physics

🛗 Jul. 2007

Feb. 2010

O Tehran, Iran Mashhad, Iran

Tools / Skills

Android

Partially Open Source Mobile Lifecycles/LiveData/Navigation/Paging/ViewModel Multidex/Test/Data Binding/WorkManager/Room Android Architecture Components/JetPack Anvil/Dagger 2/RxJava 2/Retrofit 2/.. Kotlin Multiplatform/Kotlin Coroutines Kotlin Compiler Plugin/KSP/... Compose/Data Binding/View Binding/..

- TL:DR why he's interested:
- It's partially open source OS.
- Generally interested on Mobile Technologies.

Rust

tonic/prost/openssl/tokio/flatbuffers/thrift Rc/Arc/Mutex

- Rust's type system is what you need for scale-up.
- Borrow Checker restrictly stops any memory leaks.

Podman/Docker

Buildkit/Compose/Cache

TI ·DR why he's interested:

- Reproducibility is the key to productivity. - Isolation is the key to reproducibility.

NixOS/Nix Darwin mkDrivation/mkShell

- TL:DR why he's interested: - Reproducibility is the key to productivity.
- Isolation is the key to reproducibility.
- Due to respecting to pure function, it provides better caching experience than Docker.

Software Architecture

Clean Architecture/Hexagonal Architecture Unidirectional data flow Architecture Logic Tree Architecture MVVM/MVI/MVP/RMVVM

Principle

Clean Code/SOLID Object Oriented Programming **Functional Programming** Stable Dependencies Principle Stable Abstractions Principle

Adapter/Facade/Proxy/Visitor/Delegate/... Strategy/Chain of responsibility/...

Design Pattern

Android test library JUnit/Mockito/Espresso/JaCoCo/...

adb/sdkmanager/avdmanager/...

Factory/Builder/Singleton/...

Build Tool Nix/Gradle/Cargo/Sbt/Maven/Ant/Make/...

Command Line Tool grep/sed/netstat/awk/docker/...

Development Tool

Pivotal Tracker/Jira/Jenkins/Travis/CircleCi/...

Programing Language Kotlin/Rust/Python/Java/Scala

Groovy/Dart/Javascript/Ruby...

Trunk Based development/Github flow/Git Flow Cross-functional team

Operating System

Linux(NixOS/Fedora/Ubuntu/Debian), OS X

Special Honor

- 2020 Had an offer from MobileLIVE, Toronto, Canada 2020 Had an offer from iFood, Remote
- 2019 Had an offer from Kik, Kitechener, Canada 2019 Had an offer from Letgo, Barcelona, Spain 2019 Had an offer from CRITICAL Techworks, BMW,
- Porto, Portugal 2019 Had an offer from The Next Big Thing, Berlin,
- 2018 Received result-oriented badge in Sheypoor - 2007 Ranked 44th among more than five thousand participants in the National Graduate Entrance Exam in

Language

Germany

English: Advance Farsi: Native

The latest version of this resume is available in github